

PRAKASH PRASAD

Rørsangervej 37, st. TV., København NV, 2400, Denmark

date of birth: 11 Oct. 1983 phone: +45-60633446

portfolio: www.prakashprasad.com
email: prakash@prakashprasad.com

Profile:

- Programmer with **8+ years** of programming experience.
- Extensive experience with C# and SQL.
- Collaborative and responsible developer, who excels at challenges.
- Founded an art studio in India illustrating leadership skills.

Skills In order of decreasing proficiency

Languages C#, SQL, C++, Java, C, Python, JavaScript, VBasic.

Source Control Perforce, SVN, Mercurial, Git.

Misc. XNA, PostgreSQL, Unreal Game Engine, WinForms, Actionscript, Scaleform, OpenGL, SQLite, ASP.NET,

ADO.NET.

Professional Experience

Reto-Moto Aps, Copenhagen, Denmark IT Architect/ Game Programmer/ Nov 2011 till date Game Designer

Involved in the development of the studio's free-to-play MMO game "Heroes & Generals" http://heroesandgenerals.com which combines World War II FPS gameplay with strategic planning to win the war. My role in the project is:

- **Server Backend** Designing and programming server-side event-handlers that execute a broad spectrum of tasks from the users, such as buying soldiers and equipping items on that soldier. These event-handlers cater to both a Flash based client, mobile clients as well as the game's FPS component.
- **Strategy Gameplay** Designing and programming the strategy game's main game loop, which encompasses all rules regarding the state of each battle in the war.
- Writing unit and stress tests to ensure maximum uptime of servers running the global massive multiplayer war.
- **Data Management** A large portion of the development process involves handling and processing large amounts of data related to players in the game at any given time. The data is stored on a **PostgreSQL** database server. Many tasks related to management, upkeep, and trouble-shooting on this dataset fall into my domain.
- **Game Design** I also acted as part of the "design group" to help plan the game's ideal design, and the steps involved in implementing them.

Tools: Visual Studio, PostgreSQL, Perforce, XNA

IT University of Copenhagen, Denmark | Teaching Assistant | Aug 2010 to May 2011

This role involved providing one on one support to students of the games line at the University. I assisted in two courses:

- Game Design I acted as producer in student game projects setting up milestones, pointing out workflow flaws and feature priorities.
- **Game Development** I held two part lecture series titled **"Introduction to Unreal Engine"** and provided individual advice regarding the Unreal Engine during student's project development.

Paintbox Studio, New Delhi, India Co-Founder Aug 2007 to Jan 2009

I was part of the trio that setup this 3D art studio in India. Paintbox studio is based around the objective of bringing high standard art production to the Indian market. The company is still operative and making good on their objective. Company website: www.paintbox.in

- Responsible for marketing and sales, along with managing the company's financial planning and record-keeping.
- Analyzed multimedia frameworks like XNA, TorqueX, Unreal Engine 3, Actionscript with view of incorporating them into company's business strategy.

Ernst & Young, Lyndhurst, NJ Programmer Analyst Feb 2006 to April 2007

- Designed and developed a questionnaire **web application**, which used UI elements from NetAdvantage and AJAX.NET on the ASP.NET framework. Most of the programming was done in C#, along with javascript.
- Provided support for **XML DOM parser** application which was used to transfer data from Sharepoint database to questionnaire-rendering database.
- Administered and Managed Database servers (SQL Server 2000), Windows servers and IIS.

Independent Projects

Carioca Lead Programmer May 2011 to July 2011

Carioca is an RPG game developed as part of my master thesis project on "Framework for Emergent Narrative". The project's aim was to show how simulated game systems are better equipped at creating a more immersive narrative for players – https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lhSyWZQzmTE

- Artificial Intelligence (AI) Created 3 different classes of bots; their action behaviors are defined using UnrealScript states
- Designed Al pathfinding based on Navigation Meshes.
- Designed and programmed SQLite database to store game start values, dialogue data and log gameplay debug information
- Designed and programmed **Scaleform** based player **HUD**, game's **menu system**, **dialogue screens** and to show actions of the bots.
- Developed C#/WinForms applications allowing designers to generate new population of bots, and to import dialogue XML data from FlameWind Dialogue Editor to game database.

Tools: Unreal Development Kit, Visual Studio, nFringe, UnrealScript, SQLite, SVN

Snowball Fight Lead Programmer Mar 2010 to April 2010

The project involved developing a multiplayer only third-person shooter game on the Unreal engine, where kids hit each other with snowballs – http://snowball-game.com/

- **Technical Producer** Adopted the role of liaising with the project manager and designers regarding production workflow and scheduling.
- Created the player HUD in UnrealScript.
- Programmed players to spawn with respective team colored clothes/HUD.
- Programmed the dynamic attachment of post-processor in UnrealScript so as to create a mock cel-shader effect.
- Administered game packaging and bug-fixing during the test phase.

Tools: Unreal Development Kit, Visual Studio, nFringe, UnrealScript, Mercurial

The Gods Must be Crazy

Lead Programmer

Jan 2011 (48 hours)

This game was developed during the Nordic Game Jam 2011 in Copenhagen, Denmark. The game is a 2D physics based game where players try to destroy life in a solar system by lobbing meteors. It won the **Jury's Choice Award** from games researcher Jesper Juul – https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0715frM0tnY

- Designed and programmed a 2D rendering engine written in C# and XNA.
- Designed and implemented a rudimentary physics engine including real-time collision detection based on circular hitboxes as well as the simulation of object motion in space.
- Designed and programmed a text based level editor.
- Designed and created the game's menu system.

Tools: Visual Studio, C#, XNA, SVN

Monkey of Puppets Programmer Jan 2010 (48 hours)

During the 2010 Nordic Game Jam, I worked on a 2D puzzle game where players have to guide the protagonist in 2D mazes while avoiding enemies – https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYKgVT7f-4g

- Designed and programmed a 2D tile-based engine using C# and XNA.
- Designed and implemented the player, key and door classes.
- Created a unified state management system for handling game and audio events.
- Implemented AI logic allowing bots to have line-of-sight of player and ability to track to a position.

Tools: Visual Studio, C#, XNA, SVN

MiniGolf/GnomeEngine Programmer Nov 2009 to Dec 2009

Minigolf is a 3D golf game made using the GnomeEngine which is an OpenGL/C++ library I created to provide reusable rendering and physics operations.

- Provided camera control helper functions for the user.
- Implemented texturing support (TGA file format) and 3D Model support (3DS file format).
- Designed and created a menu system with button components managed by its container menu screen and a bunch of screens managed by a MenuManager.

Tools: Visual Studio, C++, OpenGL

Education

Aug 2009 - Sep 2011 IT University of Copenhagen, **Master of Science**

Media Technology & Games - Technology Denmark

Aug 2004 - Dec 2005 Coastal Carolina University, South **Bachelor of Science**

Major: Computer Science, Minor: Applied Mathematics

Carolina, USA

Personal Information

Nationality Indian

Language Proficiency English - Fluent (written and spoken); 8.0 IELTS Overall Band Score **Interests** Photography, bouldering, paintball, video games, board games

References

Contact information for references will be furnished upon request

Tobias Larsen, Ex-Backend Programmer, Reto-Moto.

- Henrik Skov Jacobsen, Game Programmer, Reto-Moto.
- Alessandro Canossa, Ex-Lecturer (Thesis Supervisor), IT University of Copenhagen.
- Krishna Maheshwari, Director, Paintbox Studio.